Guide to the John Hope Franklin papers, 1891-2010, bulk 1950-2010 RL.10029
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Audiovisual Recordings (AV), 1959-2009; 27 boxes; 1 film can
  - Recordings of John Hope Franklin, 1960-2009 and undated; 2
    - Tobriner Memorial Lecture, 1990
      - Original VHS Videocassette, 1990 February 22 (Box AV25, Video-cassette RL10029-VHS-0178)
        Tobriner Memorial Lecture by Professor John Hope Franklin.
    - Public Education: The Reality and the Vision, undated
      - Original VHS Videocassette, undated (Box AV26, Video-cassette RL10029-VHS-0179)
        A Conversation with John Hope Franklin and David Goldfield.
    - North Carolina People Episode #2804, 1998
      - Original VHS Videocassette, 1998 July 24 (Box AV26, Video-cassette RL10029-VHS-0180)
        Episode #2804 of North Carolina People featuring Professor John Hope Franklin. Broadcast on the UNC Center for Public Television.
    - NBC Today Show, 1999 July 29
      - Original videocassette (Box AV28, Video-cassette RL.10029-VHS-0167)
    - North Carolina People, undated
      - Original VHS Videocassette (Box AV26, Video-cassette RL10029-VHS-0181)
        North Carolina People from UNC TV. Subject/Guest name: John Hope Franklin
      - Original VHS Videocassette (Box AV26, Video-cassette RL10029-VHS-0182)
    - Pembroke Forum; John Hope Franklin, Chair of the Advisory Board to the Presidential Initiative on Race, 1997
      - Original VHS Videocassette, 1997 October 13 (Box AV26, Video-cassette RL10029-VHS-0184)
        Pembroke Forum featuring John Hope Franklin the Chair of the Advisory Board to the Presidential Initiative on Race
    - Presidential Medal of Freedom Ceremony, undated
      - Original VHS Videocassette, undated (Box AV26, Video-cassette RL10029-VHS-0185)
        Excerpts showing award to Professor John Hope Franklin, recorded from C-SPAN.
  - Recordings of Others, 1959-2002 and undated; 3
    The Recordings of Others subseries contains a variety of items. Some stem from organizations Franklin was connected with, such as the Children's Defense Fund and the USSAS in Durban. Other recordings concern topics related to Franklin's work, including commercial videos on race-related issues. A smaller number of recordings include commercial musical performances, including a compilation of Civil War songs performed by a former student of Franklin, to recordings of notable writers and historians. The earliest musical recordings is from 1959, "An Evening of Spirituals" performed by African American artist Merritt Hedgeman.
    - Merritt Hedgeman, An Evening of Spirituals, 1959 July 23; 159
      - Original audiocassette (Box AV13, Audio-cassette RL10029-CS-0050)
      - Preservation master compact disc (Box AV16, Audio-cd RL10029-CD-0020)
      - Use copy compact disc (Box AV18, Audio-cd RL10029-CD-0067)
    - Studs Christmas Program, 1961 December; 160
      - Original audiocassette (Box AV13, Audio-cassette RL10029-CS-0051)
      - Preservation master compact disc (Box AV16, Audio-cd RL10029-CD-0029)
      - Use copy compact disc (Box AV18, Audio-cd RL10029-CD-0076)
    - Today Show interview of a member of JHF's staff at University of Chicago, 1968 November 18; 161
      - Original 1/4-inch Audio-reel (Box AV23, Audio-reel RL10029-RR-0016)
      - Preservation master compact disc (Box AV20, Audio-cd RL10029-CD-0120)
      - Use copy compact disc (Box AV21, Audio-cd RL10029-CD-0144)
    - Collection of songs focusing on the Civil War, Reconstruction, and North Carolina, written and sung by Bill Fesperman, 1971 December 15; 162
      - Original 1/4-inch Audio-reel (Box AV23, Audio-reel RL10029-RR-0017)
      - Preservation master compact disc (Box AV20, Audio-cd RL10029-CD-0121)
      - Use copy compact disc (Box AV21, Audio-cd RL10029-CD-0145)
    - Walter Dellinger speech to the N.C. Committee on the Bicentennial of the U.S. Constitution, 1986 January 31; 163
      - Original audiocassette (Box AV13, Audio-cassette RL10029-CS-0052)
      - Preservation master compact disc (Box AV16, Audio-cd RL10029-CD-0024)
      - Use copy compact disc (Box AV18, Audio-cd RL10029-CD-0071)
    - Klan attack on Forsyth County, Ga., Marchers, 1987 January 17; 164
      - Original VHS videocassette (Box AV8, Video-cassette RL10029-VHS-0140)
    - The Fourth Annual Martin Luther King Forum at Schomburg Library: Why We Should Teach About the Black Freedom Movement?, 1989 December 1; 165
      - Original VHS videocassette (Box AV7, Video-cassette RL10029-VHS-0120)
    - Slavery Documents, 1990 March 23; 166
      - Original compact disc (Box AV14, Audio-cd RL10029-CD-0001)
    - Marian Anderson, 1991 May 8; 167
      - Original VHS videocassette (Box AV7, Video-cassette RL10029-VHS-0135)
    - International Civil Rights Center & Museum, 1994; 168
      - Original VHS videocassette (Box AV7, Video-cassette RL10029-VHS-0128)
    - Children's Defense Fund Cease Fire! Campaign Launch, 1994 October 13; 169
      - Original VHS videocassette (Box AV8, Video-cassette RL10029-VHS-0147)
      - Original VHS videocassette (Box AV8, Video-cassette RL10029-VHS-0148)
    - Children's Defense Fund local news coverage, 1994 September; 170
      - Original VHS videocassette (Box AV8, Video-cassette RL10029-VHS-0144)
    - The Cradle of Democracy: Virginia's Historic Piedmont, Protect Historic America, 1994 September 12; 171
      - Original audiocassette (Box AV13, Audio-cassette RL10029-CS-0053)
    - Black Community Crusade for Children National Day of Action Against Violence, local news coverage, 1995 April 4; 172
      - Original VHS videocassette (Box AV8, Video-cassette RL10029-VHS-0145)
    - Children's Defense Fund Special, 1995 September 28; 173
      - Original VHS videocassette (Box AV8, Video-cassette RL10029-VHS-0146)
    - Children's Defense Fund Celebration of Self-Help House Parties, 1996; 174
      - Original VHS videocassette (Box AV8, Video-cassette RL10029-VHS-0149)
    - Children's Defense Fund Child Advocacy Ministry, 1997; 175
      - Original VHS videocassette (Box AV8, Video-cassette RL10029-VHS-0150)
    - Two Nations of Black America, 1998 February 10; 176
      - Original VHS videocassette (Box AV7, Video-cassette RL10029-VHS-0123)
    - Poet's Corner with Gloria Oden, 1999 April; 177
      - Original VHS videocassette (Box AV7, Video-cassette RL10029-VHS-0122)
    - Boycott, 2000 December 20; 178
      - Original VHS videocassette (Box AV7, Video-cassette RL10029-VHS-0131)
    - Frank Bolden: The Man Behind the Words, 2001; 179
      - Original VHS videocassette (Box AV7, Video-cassette RL10029-VHS-0139)
    - We Shall Not Be Moved, 2001; 180
      - Original VHS videocassette (Box AV7, Video-cassette RL10029-VHS-0125)
    - Mighty Times: The Legacy of Rosa Parks, 2002; 181
      - Original VHS videocassette (Box AV7, Video-cassette RL10029-VHS-0129)
    - African Folktales with the Accompanying Voices of Children and Musical Instruments and Traditional African Instruments, undated, 182
      - Original audiocassette (Box AV13, Audio-cassette RL10029-CS-0054)
    - Angels of Change, undated; 183
      - Original VHS videocassette (Box AV7, Video-cassette RL10029-VHS-0132)
    - Ida B. Wells: A Passion for Justice, undated; 184
      - Original VHS videocassette (Box AV7, Video-cassette RL10029-VHS-0137)
    - Jesse DeVore, Voices, Inc., undated; 185
      - Original 1/4-inch Audio-reel (Box AV23, Audio-reel RL10029-RR-0018)
      - Preservation master compact disc (Box AV20, Audio-cd RL10029-CD-0121)
      - Use copy compact disc (Box AV21, Audio-cd RL10029-CD-0145)
    - Jesse Jackson, undated; 186
      - Original VHS videocassette (Box AV7, Video-cassette RL10029-VHS-0124)
    - Jessye Norman: A Holiday Homecoming, undated; 187
      - Original VHS videocassette (Box AV7, Video-cassette RL10029-VHS-0121)
    - Massachusetts School of Law: Books of Our Time, undated; 188
      - Original VHS videocassette (Box AV7, Video-cassette RL10029-VHS-0133)
      - Original VHS videocassette (Box AV7, Video-cassette RL10029-VHS-0134)
    - Public Housing, undated; 189
      - Original VHS videocassette (Box AV8, Video-cassette RL10029-VHS-0142)
      - Original VHS videocassette (Box AV8, Video-cassette RL10029-VHS-0143)
    - Racist TV, undated; 190
      - Original VHS videocassette (Box AV7, Video-cassette RL10029-VHS-0127)
    - Ralph Ellison: An American Journey, undated; 191
      - Original VHS videocassette (Box AV7, Video-cassette RL10029-VHS-0130)
    - Reparations, undated; 192
      - Original DVD videodisc (Box AV14, Video-disc RL10029-DVD-0001)
    - Sing it, Tell it, undated; 193
      - Original VHS videocassette (Box AV7, Video-cassette RL10029-VHS-0138)
    - Southern Poverty Law Center Office Copy No. 11, undated; 194
      - Original VHS videocassette (Box AV8, Video-cassette RL10029-VHS-0141)
    - The First World Festival of Negro Arts, undated; 195
      - Original VHS videocassette (Box AV7, Video-cassette RL10029-VHS-0136)
    - The Klan: A Legacy of Hate in America, undated; 196
      - Original 3/4-inch videocassette (Box AV10, Video-cassette RL10029-Umatic-0004)
    - The Vernon Johns Story, undated; 197
      - Original VHS videocassette (Box AV7, Video-cassette RL10029-VHS-0126)
    - This is a Friendly World, undated; 198
      - Original 1/4-inch Audio-reel (Box AV23, Audio-reel RL10029-RR-0019)
      - Original 1/4-inch Audio-reel (Box AV23, Audio-reel RL10029-RR-0020)
      - Preservation master compact disc (Box AV20, Audio-cd RL10029-CD-0122)
      - Preservation master compact disc (Box AV20, Audio-cd RL10029-CD-0123)
      - Use copy compact disc (Box AV21, Audio-cd RL10029-CD-0146)
      - Use copy compact disc (Box AV21, Audio-cd RL10029-CD-0147)
    - UCO1, undated; 199
      - Original 1/4-inch Audio-reel (Box AV23, Audio-reel RL10029-RR-0021)
      - Original 1/4-inch Audio-reel (Box AV23, Audio-reel RL10029-RR-0022)
      - Preservation master compact disc (Box AV20, Audio-cd RL10029-CD-0124)
      - Preservation master compact disc (Box AV20, Audio-cd RL10029-CD-0125)
      - Use copy compact disc (Box AV21, Audio-cd RL10029-CD-0148)
      - Use copy compact disc (Box AV21, Audio-cd RL10029-CD-0149)
    - Unidentified lecture, undated; 200
      - Original audiocassette (Box AV13, Audio-cassette RL10029-CS-0055)
      - Original audiocassette (Box AV13, Audio-cassette RL10029-CS-0056)
      - Original audiocassette (Box AV13, Audio-cassette RL10029-CS-0057)
      - Original audiocassette (Box AV13, Audio-cassette RL10029-CS-0058)
      - Preservation master compact disc (Box AV16, Audio-cd RL10029-CD-0012)
      - Preservation master compact disc (Box AV16, Audio-cd RL10029-CD-0013)
      - Preservation master compact disc (Box AV16, Audio-cd RL10029-CD-0014)
      - Preservation master compact disc (Box AV16, Audio-cd RL10029-CD-0023)
      - Preservation master compact disc (Box AV16, Audio-cd RL10029-CD-0027)
      - Preservation master compact disc (Box AV17, Audio-cd RL10029-CD-0035)
      - Use copy compact disc (Box AV18, Audio-cd RL10029-CD-0059)
      - Use copy compact disc (Box AV18, Audio-cd RL10029-CD-0060)
      - Use copy compact disc (Box AV18, Audio-cd RL10029-CD-0061)
      - Use copy compact disc (Box AV18, Audio-cd RL10029-CD-0070)
      - Use copy compact disc (Box AV18, Audio-cd RL10029-CD-0074)
      - Use copy compact disc (Box AV19, Audio-cd RL10029-CD-0082)
    - From Slavery to Freedom, 1999
      - Original VHS Videocassette, 1999 December 18 (Box AV25, Video-cassette RL10029-VHS-0174)
        From Slavery to Freedom on Episodes 1 and 2.
        Produced by Clio, Inc. as part of their "Visualizing History" series.
      - Original VHS Videocassette, 1999 December 18 (Box AV25, Video-cassette RL10029-VHS-0175)
        From Slavery to Freedom. VHS contains Part 3.
    - North Carolina People; New South, 1998
      - Original VHS Videocassette, 1998 April 10 (Box AV26, Video-cassette RL10029-VHS-0183)
        North Carolina People episode #2740 "New South." Produced by the UNC Center for Public Television.
  - Separated Materials
    Files contain paper materials separated from AV items for preservation purposes. The items are documented in entry notes for the individual AV items the materials were found with.
    - Papers separated from audiovisual items (Box AV24)
- Correspondence (C), 1930s-2009; 38 boxes
  Series comprises personal and professional correspondence received and sent by Franklin throughout his adult life. Series is organized into subseries that reflect the original arrangement of the materials. The materials also include correspondence from Franklin's assistants, Margaret Fitzsimmons and Debi Hamlin, written on Franklin's behalf.
  The bulk of the materials makes up the General Professional and Personal Correspondence subseries. These are loosely organized by correspondent; the Professional Correspondence subseries has been further sorted by decade. Correspondence with significant or notable people and organizations have been given their own files in the Professional and Personal Name Files subseries. Additional subseries include Publisher's Correspondence, Recommendations, Declined Invitations, Advice to Authors, and Offers.
  Additional correspondence is found throughout the collection, particularly in the Advisory Board for the President's Initiative on Race (ABPIR) Series and the Service Series. The Student Files subseries in the Academia Series also includes many recommendation letters.
  Several later additions of correspondence are found at the end of some of the subseries.
  - General Professional Correspondence, 1930s-2000s
    Materials have been grouped alphabetically and then by decade. The majority of letters date from the 1990s and 2000s. A final addition of mixed general correspondence is found at the end of this series in Box C36.
    This subseries includes letters received by Franklin relating to his work as a professor, advisor, colleague, and historian. Letters occasionally include newspaper clippings, articles, and other attachments.
    - A, 1940s-2000s, 8 folders (Box C1)
    - B, 1940s-2000s, 9 folders (Box C1)
    - C, 1940s-2000s, 10 folders (Box C2)
    - D, 1940s-1990s, 4 folders (Box C2)
    - D, 2000s, 2 folders (Box C3)
    - E, 1940s-2000s, 5 folders (Box C3)
    - F, 1940s-2000s, 6 folders (Box C3)
      One disk containing electronic media has been separated from this folder. Please contact Research Services for assistance accessing that item.
    - G, 1930s-2000s, 6 folders (Box C3)
    - H, 1940s-2000s, 9 folders (Box C4)
    - I, 1940s-2000s, 4 folders (Box C4)
    - J, 1940s-1990s, 4 folders (Box C4)
    - J, 2000s, 2 folders (Box C5)
    - K, 1940s-2000s, 5 folders (Box C5)
    - L, 1940s-2000s, 7 folders (Box C5)
    - M, 1940s-1980s, 4 folders (Box C5)
    - M, 1990s-2000s, 6 folders (Box C6)
    - N, 1940s-2000s, 8 folders (Box C6)
    - O, 1940s-2000s, 3 folders (Box C6)
    - P, 1940s-2000s, 7 folders (Box C7)
    - Q, 1940s-2000s, 1 folders (Box C7)
    - R, 1940s-2000s, 7 folders (Box C7)
    - S, 1930s-1970s, 3 folders (Box C7)
    - S, 1980s-2000s, 8 folders (Box C8)
    - T, 1940s-1990s, 5 folders (Box C8)
    - T, 2000s, 2 folders (Box C9)
    - U, 1940s-2000s, 3 folders (Box C9)
    - V, 1940s-2000s, 3 folders (Box C9)
    - W-Z, 1940s-2000s, 11 folders (Box C9)
    - Additional general professional correspondence, 1935-2008 and undated; 7 folders (Box C36)
      Early correspondence sent by the Rosenwald Foundation and the Social Science Research Council relates to scholarships JHF received while a graduate student, his appointment at Brooklyn College, and congratulations on his winning the Guggenheim award in 1950. Other letters include one from the Journal of Negro History concerning a article accepted for publication, and a letter from Ralph Bunche thanking JHF for his congratulations on Bunche's Nobel Peace Prize.
  - General Personal Correspondence, 1950s-2000s
    Materials have been grouped alphabetically. Unnamed correspondence (both personal and professional) is filed at the end of the subseries. A final addition of mixed general correspondence is found at the end of this series in boxes C36-37.
    Franklin's General Personal Correspondence was largely with friends or colleagues regarding personal or private topics, such as family news, Christmas and birthday cards, and other general correspondence.
    - A-D (Box C10)
    - D-J (Box C11)
    - K-P (Box C12)
    - P-W (Box C13)
    - W-Z, and unnamed (Box C14)
    - Additional general personal correspondence, 1980s-1990s; 4 folders (Box C36)
    - Additional personal correspondence, 2000s and undated; 4 folders (Box C37)
  - Professional Correspondence Name Files, 1939-2000s and undated
    Files are arranged alphabetically by the organization or person's last name.
    Notable or significant correspondence with Franklin's professional contacts has been separated from General Correspondence into the Professional Correspondence Name Files. These files document Franklin's ongoing relationships with particular scholars and organizations.
    Among the earliest correspondence are letters to and from Will H. Alexander, Herbert Aptheker, Howard K. Beale, Paul H. Buck, W.E.B. Dubois, Franklin E. Frazier, Oscar Handlin, Harold Hyman, Charles S. Johnson, Mordecai Johnson, Alain Locke, James Shephard, and other academics who encouraged and supported Franklin in his earliest research, and foundations offering scholarships to promising graduate students. There are also single letters from Martin Luther King, Jr., Pauli Murray, and Rosa Parks.
    Additional professional correspondence can be found throughout other series, concentrated particularly in the Academia, Service, and Engagements series.
    - Abraham, Arthur (Box C15)
    - Academy of Senior Professionals at Eckerd College (Box C15)
    - Alexander, Roberta (Box C15)
    - Alexander, Will W. (Box C37)
    - American Scholar (Box C15)
    - American Visions (Box C15)
    - Anderson, Eric (Box C15)
    - Angelou, Maya (Box C15)
    - Aptheker, Herbert (Box C15)
    - Aptheker, Herbert (Box C37)
    - Army War College (Box C15)
    - Ascher, Abe (Box C15)
    - Association of Social Science Teachers in Negro Schools (Box C15)
    - Atkins, Hannah (Box C15)
    - Bacote, Clarence (Box C15)
    - Bass, Jack (Box C15)
    - B.C. Franklin Research Center (Box C15)
    - Beale, Howard K. (Box C15)
    - Beale, Howard K. (Box C37)
    - Beckum, Leonard (Box C15)
    - Bell, Derrick (Box C15)
    - Bennett, Howard (Judge) (Box OV4)
      Letter, card, and oversize clipping
    - Bennett College (Box C15)
    - Bernhard, Berle (Box C15)
    - Berkman, Dave (Box C15)
    - Berry, Wendell (Box C15)
    - Bhan, Esme (Box C15)
    - Billington, Ray A. (Box C15)
    - Black Issues in Higher Education (Box C15)
    - Black Patriots Foundation (Box C15)
    - Board of Foreign Scholarships (Box C15)
    - Bond, Julian (Box C15)
    - Bontemps, Alex (Box C15)
    - Booker T. Washington Class of 1931 (Box C15)
    - Boorstin, Samuel A. (Box C37)
    - Boorstin, Daniel and Ruth (Box C15)
    - Breiseth, Christopher N. (Box C15)
    - British Broadcasting Corporation (Box C15)
    - Brodie, H. Keith (Box C15)
    - Brokaw, Tom (Box C15)
    - Brookings Institution (Box C15)
    - Brooklyn College (Box C15)
    - Buck, Paul H. (Box C15)
    - Buck, Paul H. (Box C37)
    - Bunche, Ralph J. (Box C15)
    - Burchard, Peter (Box C15)
    - Burkett, Randall K. (Box C15)
    - Burkhalter, Mildred (Box C15)
    - Burton, Vernon (Box C15)
    - Bush, George H.W. and Laura (Box C15)
    - California, University of: Berkeley (Box C15)
    - California, University of: Los Angeles (Box C15)
    - Cambridge, University of (Box C15)
    - Cameron Park Elementary School (Box C15)
    - Carrington, Paul D. and Bessie (Box C15)
    - Carter, Jimmy (Box C15)
    - Castle, Elizabeth (Box C15)
    - Caughey, John and La Ree (Box C15)
    - Center for Advanced Studies in the Behavioral Sciences (Box C16)
    - Central Virginia Educational Television Corporation (Box C16)
    - Chafe, William H. (Box C16)
    - Chambers, Julius L. (Box C16)
    - Chase, Hal S. (Box C16)
    - Chicago, University of (Box C16)
    - Children's Defense Fund (Box C16)
    - Cincinnati, University of (Box C16)
    - City University of New York (Box C16)
    - Clark, Kenneth B. (Box C16)
    - Clinton, William and Hillary (Box C16)
    - Clinton, William J. (Box C37)
    - William Clinton Library (NARA) (Box C16)
    - Cohen, William (Box C16)
    - Collier-Thomas, Bettye (Box C16)
    - Congress of the United States (Box C16)
    - Cook, Samuel DuBois (Box C16)
    - Cornell University (Box C16)
    - Cornish, Dudley T. (Box C16)
    - Conference Board of Associated Research Councils (Box C16)
    - Crisis Magazine (Box C16)
    - Cummings, Livingston (Box C37)
      Includes long draft of Cummings' research on cross-burning in the South.
    - Curry, Richard (Box C16)
    - Curti, Merle Eugene (Box C37)
    - Daly, Charles U. (Box C16)
    - Dartmouth College (Box C16)
    - Davidson, Cathy N. (Box C16)
    - Dawson, Horace G. (Box C16)
    - Dellinger, Hampton (Box C16)
    - Dellinger, Walter (Box C16)
    - Dillon, Wilton (Box C16)
    - Ditchley Foundation (Box C16)
    - Drimmer, Mel (Box C16)
    - DuBois, W.E.B. (Box C16)
    - Dubois, W.E.B. and Shirley (Box C37)
    - Duke, Anthony Drexel (Box C16)
    - Duke Endowment (Box C16)
    - Duke University (Box C16)
    - Duke University: Center for Documentary Studies (Box C16)
    - Duke University: Department of History (Box C16)
    - Duke University: Nasher Museum of Art (Box C16)
    - Duke University: Duke University Libraries (Box C16)
    - Duke University: Duke University Medical Center (Box C16)
    - Duke University: School of Law (Box C16)
    - Durham, City of (Box C16)
    - Durham County Library (Box C16)
    - Durham Symphony (Box C16)
    - Eastern Illinois University (Box C16)
    - Edwards, Lillie (Box C17)
    - Eisenstadt, Abe (Box C17)
    - Ellsworth, Scott (Box C17)
    - Fairview Free Public Library (Box C17)
    - Fellowship of Southern Writers (Box C17)
    - Ferris, Bill (Box C17)
    - Finkelman, Paul (Box C17)
    - Fisk University (Box C17)
    - Fisk University: Alumni Associations (Box C17)
    - Fitzsimmons, Margaret (Box C17)
    - Ford Foundation (Box C17)
    - Franklin Humanities Institute (Box C17)
    - Franklin, Vincent P. (Box C17)
    - Frazier, E. Franklin (Box C17)
    - Frazier, E. Franklin (Box C37)
    - Frey, Sylvia (Box C17)
    - Friday, William (Box C17)
    - Fulbright Association (Box C17)
    - Future America Research Institute (Box C17)
    - Gates, Henry Louis "Skip" Jr. (Box C17)
    - Gates, Paul W. (Box C17)
    - Genovese, Eugene (Box C37)
    - Georgetown University Law Center (Box C17)
    - George Washington University (Box C17)
    - Gillis, Malcolm (Box C17)
    - Glasgow, University of (Box C17)
    - Gore, Albert and Tipper (Box C17)
    - Gray, Hanna (Box C17)
    - Greene, Charity (Box C17)
    - Guggenheim Foundation (Box C17)
    - Hamlin, Debi (Box C17)
    - Hampton Institute (Box C17)
    - Handlin, Oscar (Box C17)
    - Harding, Vincent (Box C17)
    - Harlan, Louis R. (Box C17)
    - Harvard University (Box C17)
    - Higginbotham, Leon A. and Evelyn Brooks (Box C17)
    - Hilenski, Ferdinand (Box C17)
    - Hill, Anthony Cromwell (Box C18)
    - Hill, Walter B. Jr. (Box C18)
    - Hine, Darlene Clark (Box C18)
    - Hirsch-Weber, Wolfgang (Box C18)
    - Hogan and Hartson (Box C18)
    - Holloway, Karla (Box C18)
    - Honda, Sozo (Box C37)
      Thick folder of correspondence.
    - Howard University (Box C18)
    - Howard University Gallery of Art (Box C18)
    - Huggins, Nathan (Box C18)
    - Hurwitz, Samuel and Edith (Box C18)
    - Hyman, Harold (Box C18)
    - Hyman, Harold (Box C37)
    - Igwemadu, Felix (Box C18)